Welcome to the algorithm section.
An algorithm is a set of instructions designed to perform a specific task.
Algorithms can be simple and complex depending on what you want to achieve.
We can use algorithms to describe ordinary activities in our everyday life.
For example, we can consider a recipe as an algorithm for cooking a particular food.
OK, so these are the steps, these are the algorithm, how to prepare a pit.
Algorithms and computers in computer systems and algorithm is a logic written by software developers
in any programming language of their choice.
But there are few sets of rules that we need to remember while designing algorithms.
They are the input.
There should be one or more values to be applied in the algorithm.
If there is no input given, what output would the algorithm produce?
So we need to specify and get the data from the input.
The outcome, at least one output should be produced.
There is no use of designing an algorithm, it does not produce any result.
The third thing that we need to take care about when designing algorithm is that efficiency, it should
be efficient in terms of compute and memory.
The output produced should be correct and fast.
So this is why we study that time complexity and space complexity simplicity.
The algorithm should be it should not be overly complex.
We need to make it simple as much as you can.
Scalability.
The algorithm must be able to scale without changing the core logic.
We can apply it to do like millions of device or hundreds of devices.
OK, so the algorithms in computer.
Let's now build a simple algorithm, which adds two numbers for fulfilling the above prerequisites.
OK, so we have seen this in the previous in the first first introduction of the course, but I will
make a simple introduction and overview now in order to move next to their sorting and searching algorithms.
So in order to add two numbers, we start.
We start the software or the algorithm step to declare variables number one and number two and.
Some variables we read that values a number one and number two entered by the user.
We add number one and number two and assign that value to some variable and we display some.
And then we stop the program.
This is very simple to make an algorithm that adds to no.
I choose to implement in it in Java language.
You can implement it in any programming language of your choice.
OK.
So I will implement this program that adds two numbers and Jeff.
OK, we have some two numbers.
We start by creating the number number one and number two.
Let me see.
So we define our main method and we create and no one.
And numb to variables and that some valuable.
OK, so we have created the three variables here.
Now we need to assign the values to them by using the scanner.
So I get the scanner and I display for the user and throw the first number and the user enters the first
number.
And I took the number that entered from the user from the scanner dock next and and I assign it to number
one.
Suppose that the user entered five at the first number, we need also to get the second number from
the user.
I will display system to print a message telling him to enter the second number.
Number two equal to the source or scanner dot next.
And so we have a signing and this and a signed getting the value from the user to assign it to that
number to value the user and 37 again.
Then scanner that close sum equal to number plus and number one plus number two.
So I am assigning that as I'm getting the value.
Number one, go to the memory and get the number one value and go to the box number two and get the
value of it.
Add it together.
Add them together five and seven.
It will give you 12 and assign it and stored it into there.
Some value system that added print the sum of two VAT in numbers is the variable sum, so go and get
the variable sum.
This will display for us some of the numbers.
12.
OK.
This is how we make an algorithm to add two numbers in computers.
I should remember you that we have talked about the algorithms and took many examples of algorithms
in there in the beginning of this course.
So please guys, go back to the beginning of the course and see these videos about the variables.
Data types algorithm one two three four and the examples and data structure.
Add definitions and the analysis of the algorithm.
OK.
They are very important, and I should consider you that you have learned them and you have mastered
them in order to continue.